[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The primary sex organ in the male is the",
    "options": [
      "penis",
      "scrotum",
      "testes",
      "all of these",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["testes"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The production of spermatozoa is by a process known as",
    "options": [
      "spermatogenesis",
      "spermiogenesis",
      "steroidogenesis",
      "oogenesis",
      "spermatid"
    ],
    "answer": ["spermatogenesis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The following are accessory reproductive cells except",
    "options": [
      "epidydymis",
      "ductus deferens",
      "ejaculatory duct",
      "urethra",
      "testes"
    ],
    "answer": ["testes"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The normal scrotal temperature for spermatogenesis is",
    "options": ["25◦c", "27◦c", "35◦c", "37 ◦c", "39◦c"],
    "answer": ["35◦c"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The blood testes barrier is provided byt the following",
    "options": [
      "seminiferous tubules",
      "sertoli cells",
      "epidydymis",
      "testosterone",
      "scrotum"
    ],
    "answer": ["sertoli cells"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "In what part of the mature spermatozoa are lytic enzymes stored?",
    "options": ["DNA", "nucleus", "acrosome", "mitochondria", "cytoplasm"],
    "answer": ["acrosome"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Normal sperm count is between",
    "options": [
      "20,000 – 50,000",
      "20 -50 million",
      "50- 120 million",
      "150 – 120 million",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["50- 120 million"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The following are component of seminal fluid except",
    "options": [
      "spermine",
      "fructose",
      "fibrinogen",
      "glycogen",
      "prostaglandin"
    ],
    "answer": ["glycogen"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The primary sex organ in the female is",
    "options": ["vagina", "breast", "ovary", "uterus", "cervix"],
    "answer": ["ovary"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Fertilization occurs normally in the",
    "options": ["ovary", "uterine tube", "uterus", "cervix", "vagina"],
    "answer": ["ovary"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following is regarded as the hormone of pregnancy",
    "options": [
      "oestrogen",
      "testosterone",
      "progesterone",
      "corpus luteum",
      "oxytocin"
    ],
    "answer": ["progesterone"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "The following are signs of ovolution except",
    "options": [
      "change is basal body temperature",
      "mid-cycle pain",
      "menstruation",
      "cervical mucus discharge",
      "breast tenderness"
    ],
    "answer": ["change is basal body temperature"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Oogenesis is the development of the",
    "options": ["zygote", "embryo", "ovum", "ovary", "fetus"],
    "answer": ["ovum"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Oestrogen is secreted by the following except",
    "options": [
      "corpus luteum",
      "theca interna",
      "granulose cells",
      "all of these",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["none of these"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "With respect to the ovary, the first two weeks of the menstrual cycle is referred to as",
    "options": [
      "menstrual phase",
      "follicular phase",
      "proliferative phase",
      "luteal phase",
      "secretory phase"
    ],
    "answer": ["menstrual phase"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The onset of menstruation is known as",
    "options": ["puberty", "maturity", "menopause", "menarche", "period"],
    "answer": ["menarche"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "The duration of pregnancy in women from the last menstrual period is approximately",
    "options": ["36 weeks", "38 weeks", "40 weeks", "42 weeks", "9 months"],
    "answer": ["40 weeks"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "When a sperm fertilizes an ovum it forms",
    "options": ["morula", "blastocyst", "zygote", "embryo", "trophoblast"],
    "answer": ["zygote"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Early pregnancy is detected by the presence of",
    "options": [
      "oestrogen",
      "human chorionic gonadotropin",
      "progesterone",
      "human placenta lactogen",
      "human placenta thyrotropin"
    ],
    "answer": ["human chorionic gonadotropin"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The following are placenta hormones except",
    "options": [
      "oxytocin",
      "estrogen",
      "progesterone",
      "human chorionic gonadotropin",
      "human placenta lactogen"
    ],
    "answer": ["oxytocin"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Child birth is known as",
    "options": [
      "pregnancy",
      "expulsion",
      "parturition",
      "lactation",
      "menopause"
    ],
    "answer": ["parturition"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Milk ejection reflex is inhibited by",
    "options": ["prolactin", "oxytocin", "relaxin", "inhibin", "oestrogen"],
    "answer": [""],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "The average age for menopause is",
    "options": [
      "15-45 years",
      "15-55 years",
      "35 -45 years",
      "45 – 55 years",
      "55 – 65 years"
    ],
    "answer": [""],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "In man chromosomes have the following pairs of autosomes",
    "options": ["46", "44", "23", "22", "2"],
    "answer": ["22"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The transmission of discrete traits from each parents is termed",
    "options": [
      "segregation",
      "inheritance",
      "phenotype",
      "genotype",
      "gender"
    ],
    "answer": ["inheritance"],
    "explanation": "",
    "topic": "Reproductive physiology"
  }
]
